<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-23T17:47:52-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Olivia Figueira</title><subtitle>Summer 2020 DREU Project Site</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Week 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 2" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week2/">&lt;p&gt;This week I attended a meeting with the entire lab of my project mentor, Dr. Wang. The meeting was at 7am PDT, since that is 9am CT, so this is an aspect of virtual DREU participation that I had not thought about until Monday when I had the meeting, but it went well despite how early the meeting was! I met other PhD students in Dr. Wang’s lab and another undergraduate research assistant who will be working on another project this summer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week I attended a meeting with the entire lab of my project mentor, Dr. Wang. The meeting was at 7am PDT, since that is 9am CT, so this is an aspect of virtual DREU participation that I had not thought about until Monday when I had the meeting, but it went well despite how early the meeting was! I met other PhD students in Dr. Wang’s lab and another undergraduate research assistant who will be working on another project this summer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/week1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1" /><published>2020-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/week1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/week1/">&lt;p&gt;Prior to starting my DREU virtual program at UIUC, I met with my two mentors to discuss project ideas. I decided on a deep fake generation project, which is a project in Dr. Wang’s lab. Dr. Khurana said she will still stay connected to serve as a mentor for other topics, such as graduate school, so it is great to have two mentors!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday of this week, I met with Dr. Wang and discussed next steps. I began reading related papers and prior work that has been done so that I would be ready on Wednesday to meet the rest of the project group, including three PhD students, and discuss next steps for the project as a whole. This week I also attended the weekly CS REU Lunch &amp;amp; Learn event on networking and learned about how networking plays a role in graduate school and beyond. It was a great event to learn about how networking is an important skill to cultivate and practice early on in my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the week, I explored some open-source methods for deep-fake generation for us to possibly use in our project. I worked on trying to run them locally to get a sense of how they worked, and also to see if they could be used for our purposes in terms of generating specific styles within images. I will soon gain access to the lab’s servers to run these on their GPUs since deep learning for image generation is computationally intensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great start to the program, and I am excited to learn more!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Prior to starting my DREU virtual program at UIUC, I met with my two mentors to discuss project ideas. I decided on a deep fake generation project, which is a project in Dr. Wang’s lab. Dr. Khurana said she will still stay connected to serve as a mentor for other topics, such as graduate school, so it is great to have two mentors!</summary></entry></feed>